Edison Abahurire

New Jersey, United States



abahedison@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/edisonabahurire



(303) 941-4313



https://www.eabahurire.com/

Summary

I'm a motivated, enthusiastic and Proficient software engineer with 5 years experience building data processing pipelines, Web Applications and data visualization dashboards.

I'm seeking opportunities that will expose me to challenging projects with highly experienced teams, that I can learn from and contribute to.

Specialties:

AWS Cloud, Data Engineering, Back-End Web Development, Data analytics, Data Visualization, Open Source, Machine learning, AGILE, Project Management, Coaching & Mentoring.

Experience



C Data Engineer (Remote)

Cobblestone Energy

Mar 2019 - Present (2 years 4 months +)

- · Built and deployed an Apache Airflow and Prefect ETL pipelines that query XML data from third party REST APIs, FTPs and PostreSQL Databases to analyze the data and write results back to our internal Data Warehouses. Deployed the Dockerised applications on AWS ECR and Kubernetes EKS.
- Led the development of a real-time Bigdata processing application that does numerical analysis on over 100GB of data daily using Python3, Pandas, Reddis, SQLAlchemy, RabbitMQ, STOMP, Sentry and ELK stack. Hosted the application using AWS services EC2, ECR, ECS, SQS, SNS, S3, CloudWatch and AWS CodeDeploy for CI/CD Pipelines.
- Built a Multi-function Webserver that contained WebSocket server using Python Tornado to stream real-time data from a Message Queue that feeds from analytics pipelines and aREST API webserver that feeds from Reddis caching Engine and does validations, authentication and JSON response Pagination.
- · Worked with a front-end team to build a 10 Window Node JS / Electron JS Desktop application that fed from a WebSocket and REST APIs to Visualize data using ES6 JavaScript libraries (Chart js, d3 js, React js) with a secure authentication layer.
- Built a Flask Web Application that uses performance trackers and Linux Log integrations to monitor, control data processing applications using an Web dashboard powered by Bootstrap 4, C3 JS and deployed the app on AWS Lambda.

Technical Team Lead

Cobblestone Energy

Nov 2019 - Jun 2020 (8 months)

- · Led weekly sprints planning and retrospectives as part of agile project management practices and regularly attended meetings with management to report on technical project progress.
- Led the hiring of 4 new developers to the team by creating job descriptions, advertising, jointly interviewing candidates and mentoring new hires on our tech-stack and development workflow.

· Regularly conducted project reviews and code reviews to ensure that all projects met technical specification like full technical documentation, 80% unit tests coverage, proper git workflow.

EDU Bootcamp Instructor

Outbox Uganda

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019 (6 months)

 Led the curriculum development, conducted learner training sessions and tracked learning progress by reviewing daily assignments and evaluating capstone projects. Tech used: JavaScript, NodeJS, React

Volunteer Learning Facilitator - (Paid Opportunity)

Andela

Mar 2018 - Mar 2019 (1 year 1 month)

• Directly trained and facilitated over 500 learners in the Level-Up program that seeks to empower technology enthusiasts from different Fields with basic software development skills and accelerating their path to start careers as software developers.

Automation Developer

BotsMart

Mar 2018 - Mar 2019 (1 year 1 month)

At Botsmart, We developed business Automation software for E-Commerce sellers.

- Managed projects by communicating with clients, drafting technical specifications, assigned projects to other contractors and build data-driven applications for clients.
- Built a Ebay & Amazon Sales Automation Django web application that gueried SOAP and REST APIs, listened for Web-hook signals to automatically ship orders and visualized the sales operation and stock monitoring to the sellers through a web visualization dashboard built using HTM5 and Bootstrap3.
- Built a Stock quantity monitoring application for online stores on Amazon and shopify and automatically adjust prices and restock goods when needed.

Contract Software Engineer

Fiverr US

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Worked as a freelance developer on Fiverr (A freelance platform). Examples include:

- Built a Milti-coin Crypto currency trading bot that was able to execute trades in 100 micro-seconds using the BITTREX REST API and Python Tkinter Desktop app library.
- Built a job aggregation web application that conducted Large scale data mining using Requests, followed by data cleansing and warehousing the data feeds into a MongoDB database.

Education



🙀 Ndejje University

Bachelors of Science, Civil Engineering 2012 - 2016